MIT study that said people use chat GPT
get dumber. Line. Uh-oh. We don't think
an AI is going to replace a human, but
you got to start using AI. The one thing
that's powerful about human ingenuity,
which is also why I think AI won't
replace us, there is a kind of sheer
will that entrepreneurs and builders and
just human ingenuity has. The kind of
ingenuity that had us survive crisis and
wars and all these problems are the same
ingenuity that we have to basically
build companies and build and businesses
and, you know, see world opportunities
that others don't.
>> 2024 was kind of like solar for new
users. These are pre-seed, tier one
speed back startup. They're asking the
question, should we use AI? And then
2025 was, how should we use AI? What
we're seeing this year across all the
segments and industry is, how do we
operationalize AI across every segment
of our business? We're all talking
about, you know, one person sort of, you
know, companies because an AI agent can
do so much work for you. Tokenize or
die. If you don't have a token strategy,
if you're not tokenized, you will lose
against the company that is tokenizing.
There are all these technological shifts
that happen that basically you have to
be ready for to address these new
markets. You should be testing multiple
things concurrently. There's no reason
why you can't do that. If you're
leveraging these agent coding tools like
Cursor or Mercurio or Cloud Code, you
have multiple windows opening [music]
running simultaneously, running a
different agent workflow, and getting to
a point where you don't even just have a
POC. I've set up production ready
a tool deployed in the cloud, built to
scale for nothing. So, you can get
credits through different cloud
providers like AWS Activate. So, there's
no excuse not to be able to go to market
quickly. The ability to become an expert
in everything is so much more valuable
than ever before. And you can also fail
fast.
>> We wanted to take them away from the
chat GPT search experience. That
experience itself limits you. So, if you
go into a website to experiencing like
search, you immediately start thinking,
what should I ask it? That's not the way
that you're supposed to frame it. Oh, it
can actually respond in this manner. And
then when you begin from that level, the
imagination of a The difference between
somebody that succeeds as a founder or a
group of founders or somebody that
doesn't are the ones that are committed
to that learning experience and dive in
deep and you understand, you know, how
to use these tools, how not to use these
tools, what their limits are, what these
limits aren't, and then the light bulb
moment happens.
When capital meets infrastructure, we
have Yat Siu from Animoca Brands and Ian
Holt from AWS.
>> This is probably one of the most
important conversation you will be
watching if you're builder or an
investor that is interested in tech.
Hello guys. Hi. Thank you for having us.
How are you feeling? There's a lot of
energy. Yeah. Yeah. It's a lot of
energy. I always, you know, if the
markets are down, which they are a
little bit in crypto, shall we say?
I tell everyone just come to a crypto
conference and re-energize. And, you
know, I would say true to form consensus
has been that.
See, that's that's the most interesting
part cuz every time when I go to a
conference, we talk to builders and
everyone's so excited.
>> That's right.
But the sentiment and, you know, among
retail investors, it feels a little
different.
>> I think we need to distinguish between
builders and investors as well, and
particularly retail investors who are
busy operating a little bit on fear cuz
they have uncertainty. They don't
understand what's going on. And it's not
just about what's happening in crypto.
It's all macro, right? You know, what's
happening with Iran, you know, what's
happening with war. Is it is it good for
the economy or not? You know, all these
things that happen all at the same time.
We just don't know, right? And that
uncertainty is unsettling for
everything. It's not just it's it's not
just not just crypto, right? But the
builders, they see a future, right? If
you're a builder, it doesn't matter if
it's AI or crypto or whatever. They kind
of all sort of intersecting anyway.
You're you're not here for today. You're
here for tomorrow. And if you're excited
about tomorrow,
this is great. So, come to conferences
like this to see tomorrow, right?
And you guys are building towards
tomorrow. So, basically you decide what
tomorrow looks like. That's my
interpretation,
right? [laughter] That's a bit bold.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, I would just say um
at AWS, we provide the infrastructure
Yeah. uh for the builders. They're the
ones that are innovating. Yeah, so from
our perspective, we're democratizing
access to technology. The builders of
today that are innovating uh for
tomorrow, whether those are students
um or you know, tier one invested VC
startups from pre-seed to series B, they
have access to the very same tools. Yes.
And so, you know, what I also noticed,
um you know, conferences like this, uh
outside of the sentiment that we see on
on the media, is uh you know, the
convergence is real, right? The
convergence that we're seeing, um you
know, with whether it's robotics or, you
know, AI coding accelerating workloads,
uh is happening here. Um and so, outside
of trading markets, um that's energy
that that we're seeing. So, And I think
just to add to that, you know, when you
build the tools for that, and it makes
it easier for innovators to come in,
they can ideate and focus on creativity,
rather than just the tech. I mean, you
know, I was there for the early days of
the internet, right? And I remember, to
set up a web server, I had to buy my own
box. I had to literally build it. Uh and
of course, today, I can do everything
virtually. I just do it on the
dashboard, and voila, I have a server.
And the abstraction layer goes even
higher and higher, between applications,
between services. And this is the thing
about blockchain. Blockchain is another
one of those layers that abstracts
essentially the security layer of
anything that has value, essentially,
whether it's financial, whether it's
asset holding. You know, you know, one
of the big topics last year was
prediction markets, like Polymarket.
I don't think a lot of people know that
Polymarket was built on blockchain.
I don't think a lot of people care.
However, Polymarket would not have been
able to be built in the speed and the
manner in which it has, if it wasn't for
blockchain. Because think about what it
would take to build an infrastructure
that can handle your money, that can put
a bet on the millions of dollars of
size, that can do all that type of
stuff. You have to have to sort of hire
someone that basically can build like a
quasi mini bank,
which would cost not millions, but
probably hundreds of millions of dollars
infrastructure. That infrastructure is
not just available for Polymarket, is
available from the 16-year-old to
14-year-old, to the 70-year-old to
80-year-old, and they can all innovate
on top of it, add vibe coding to it,
and, you know, my mom can start coding
financial applications, if she wanted
to, because the hard part is taken care
of, right? And so, I think we're
entering a world that's going to be much
more creative, which is why we're also
seeing a lot more startups and
entrepreneurs. That's actually
accelerating. It's not declining. Um
I remember being a startup and an
entrepreneur in the '90s. Hm. It's a
long time ago. Um meant you were
unemployed. That's really what it was.
Uh nobody would hire you, so you start
your own company, right? Um and now it's
kind of expected almost, right? You If
you If you If you go to your parents and
you say, especially Chinese parents or
maybe Asian parents generally, and you
say, "Hey, you know, I'm going to do my
own startup." Yeah. Try that 20 years
ago, right? Um and now it's like,
Okay. Go ahead. Let's go ahead. That's
cool, right? Um so, yeah, it's changed a
lot. Do you think capital decides where
technology goes, or is it the other way
around? You know, I I don't think uh
those are opposing. Mhm. Um I think they
compound each other. So, if you start
thinking about investment without
infrastructure, that's speculation. You
start talking about uh infrastructure
without investments, that's um you know,
unused compute. So, um
they're not opposing forces, they're
compounding forces in my view. Yeah. And
I think also, just to add on that, I
mean, the one thing that's powerful
about human ingenuity, which is also why
I think AI won't replace us, right? Even
though we're talking about AGI and all
kind of stuff, which is a different
topic altogether, uh is that there is a
kind of sheer will that entrepreneurs
and builders and just human ingenuity
has. Uh you know, the kind of ingenuity
that had us survive crises and wars and
all these problems are the same
ingenuity that we have to basically
build companies and build in businesses
and, you know, see world opportunities
that others don't, right?
>> Mhm. And then they create this kind of
impact. And now, because the cost of
that deployment has gone lower and lower
and lower, I mean, we're all talking
about, you know, one-person sort of, you
know, companies uh because an AI agent
can do so much work for you um and it's
produced over time. I mean, you know,
you had to hire so many more people just
to run a website, and now you have
basically just do-it-yourself for
instance as an example. That type of
stuff makes it just possible to just
grow, and the cost isn't that high
anymore, right?
>> Okay. Um so so I think the you know when
we look at for instance our investment
side cuz we have a lot of them, right?
The uh the sort of seed investing
startup phase was often I have an idea.
And this is what I need to get my idea
going. Okay, fine. Here's the equity.
Here's the money I just but he didn't
have a product. Now seed is here's my
product. It's built. Uh it doesn't
really quite have maybe product market
fit, but maybe you can help me with
this. It's completely different. We're
basically evolved to really the stage in
investing of a seed company is much more
like a series A-ish type company uh or
pre-series A say even 10 years ago,
right? Um so the cost is low, and the
risk is much lower as well.
>> People are talking about AI agents, but
I want to know how far away
from you know people actually building
companies with AI agents. How far are
we? What we're seeing uh from builders
is uh as fast as it's moved, uh there's
still a gap, right? So there's a there's
a big gap between an agent uh
buying an airplane ticket versus an
agent
>> Oh, yeah, yeah. For sure, for sure.
Right? And so we're clearly in category
one. Um
>> uh there's a ways to go to get to
category two. Uh we're seeing glimpses
of it.
>> Mhm. Um but we're not quite there yet.
Is it Is it easier for let's say if I'm
a solopreneur, it's easier for me to you
know try out AI agents and all these
different tools.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. But when we talk about
big companies, they're very careful when
it comes to
>> think there's a different there's a
different perspective as well. When we
come about big companies,
>> Yeah.
>> there's a lot of private data that they
have to protect.
>> Mhm. So it's about policy. I mean, you
know uh I don't think many corporations
will be happy to install open claw right
into their local servers. I mean, no in
their local infrastructure. That would
be a problem because they're going to do
and see stuff that is like what what is
all this about? However, any of your
solopreneur or a small office, the risk
is so much lower and you can experiment
around that. Um, but I think what you
saw with open cloud it kind of opened up
the possibility to say, "Wait, hold on.
We can kind of do this stuff." And to
your point, it's uh, you know, again,
because we don't think an AI is going to
replace a human, but the instrumentation
is going to be happening through an AI
agent who can do all this stuff for you
as well. Right? So, you don't have to do
all the minutia, set up the GitHub, set
up the infrastructure, even write down
the sort of draft email, that kind of
stuff. It can do 90% of that or 95% of
that. And then you go in at the final
stages and edit and review. So, you have
to understand it, right? It's not going
to It's going to write well for you, but
you still have to know how to write,
right? If you don't know how to write,
then you know, whether it's code or
whether it's English or whether it's
Chinese, if you don't know how to do
that, it's not going to help you, right?
Uh, so you still need the foundations,
but when you have that, it can be a
really, really powerful agent. Um, the
other thing, of course, is uh, what I
find really powerful with you know, what
we have with Animal Combinations, which
is our own sort of AI agent, is it's a
way in which an agent can neutrally
organize essentially collaborative
workspaces in really um, a sort of
apolitical way. Cuz you know what?
Well, so, if an AI agent basically gives
you an output or makes a suggestion or
even says it's a dumb idea, you won't be
offended quite the same way, right? But
it's very different if a coworker you
work together with basically says, "That
is stupid." I'm not saying that an AI
agent should say that, but the criticism
is very different. And so, they're
actually great arbiters, not because
they're the ones that have the final
judgment, but you will look at it not in
the same way, right? And the other thing
is that um, because you know, AI agents
like this have precision memory, they
can basically recollect stuff for you on
instruction that you might forget.
Because, you know, um,
we have one side, incredible creativity
and that kind of consciousness that AI
doesn't have, but that same creativity,
because we have feelings and we have
emotions, can impact us in ways that an
AI will not, right? And so, what we're
seeing right now is that an AI agent is
going to be in every part of your
workspace to assist and support you, not
to replace you, and then basically to
accelerate your work effort.
Uh and and also in in family planning,
in sort of life schedules, calendar,
booking tickets, right? I mean, that's
going to do a lot, right? As you said.
Um
I know, I think you know, we're in Hong
Kong. We get spoiled in Hong Kong a
little bit because we have a lot of
help. Mhm. Most of the world does not,
right? So so most of the world could
take good use of an AI agent like that.
Yeah, I would just add to I mean, you
asked about entrepreneurs. Yeah, touched
on um you know, data sovereignty and you
know, the skepticism around trust
related to you know, open thought and
enterprise. Um I will tell you from an
infrastructure perspective, you know, if
you look back two years in in 2024
versus 2025 versus this year,
um we're definitely seeing shifts
happening. So, you know, 2024 was kind
of like in this is solarpreneurs, these
are
um you know, pre-seed tier ones to be
backed, startups, these are enterprises.
Across the spectrum, across the segment,
across geos. They're asking the
question, should we use AI, right? In
2024, Yeah. And then 2025 was not should
we use AI, how should we use AI. Right.
Right? And so, what we're seeing this
year across all those segments and
industry, um is how do we operationalize
AI across every segment of our business.
And so, um
yeah, these things
uh are are happening. Um
there's still a gap, like I said,
between you know, booking the airplane
tickets and running your business, but
that reality is fast approaching. You've
seen a lot of builders. What are some,
you know, things and trends that you've
seen that excites you the most? You
know, I cover agentic coding tools.
Okay. Yeah, so at AWS, we have a
flagship tool called Kyro, um but we
also support, you know, Anthropic Claude
code uh natively within Bedrock. Um you
know, I work with a lot of startups that
are supporting a variety of other
agentic coding tools. So, what I've seen
um you know, as as a developer in the
industry for a very long time
um
is we're seeing a 10x output in in
in
from developers. And so, you know, I'm
working with senior-level developers
that had started tinkering with these
tools a few years ago. It wasn't really
working. It was creating all this slop.
The ones that are fully embracing it and
they're actually not writing any code.
So, you start talking about, you know,
two-week sprints being conducted in a
day. You know, there's technology around
that around you know, conversion between
you know, sprints to bolts. And so, what
took teams of people
you know, to develop product in three or
six months is now being done in weeks.
And that's again across across segments,
geos, and and enterprises to to
startups. So,
that's what I'm seeing is really an
acceleration by leveraging these agentic
coding tools. I mean, we're particularly
excited about how the entire framing of
the web is basically changing into one
where maybe this potentially could be
one of the biggest challenges for at
least the incumbent platforms.
And and the reason why is it because the
biggest business model for them has been
advertising? Okay. And when you think
about advertising
basically in an agentic world like we're
moving into sort of you know, web three
was the foundation that layer where you
could have ownership through blockchain.
And basically I don't know if you want
to call it web four, but essentially the
agentic web effectively allows you to
pull all this information. We're still
used to going somewhere to pull
information. And we're not used to
getting this information pushed to us
because there's a lot of slop. As in
even an AI recommendation engine
typically will send you stuff that you
don't want. So, you don't really care
about it. You want to go to the
destination. And if you look at ChatGPT
as the sort of OG of this sort of you
know, LLM moment, this sort of ChatGPT
moment as I say,
the interface was search.
Mhm. It wasn't a special innovation. It
wasn't like an agent talking to you. Uh
it was basically just a better search.
And many many companies are already
saying, "Wait, hold on a second. I'm not
actually getting a I'm getting less
clicks to my website cuz now if I'm
going to Google, Gemini is giving you
everything you need to know. I don't
have to hop into that next stage,
right?" So, there's going to be this
whole movement around, "Okay, how do I
get my fair share?" You know, YouTube
had to have content ID with the
creators. There's going to be a version
around that. There's going to be a whole
movement around, you know, it's already
happening with MCP servers, right? So,
we're moving from HTTP to MCP, right?
The user is getting everything delivered
to it through the agent, right? Uh
whether it's their messenger, whether
it's whatever application that you're
using. Um and the entire framing of the
web is going to change from the way that
we're experiencing it more efficiently,
more faster. But also as a result of
that, this is why we think the token
economy has become so powerful because
how are all of those sort of MCP sort of
servers are going sort of exchange value
with each other? It's going to be
through a token infrastructure, which is
basically one that is something that you
can verifiably prove. Whether it's a
stable coin or another token, that's
kind of beside the point. It's like,
"Oh, I know this is real." Right? Uh and
then by the way, this is also why
digital identity becomes so critically
important. Uh which is why we're
building rails around that, too, because
I need to know whether this agent is
verified. Right? We're going to have
more agents transacting than humans. And
I don't mean just money. I mean like
taking data, doing that kind of stuff,
right? How do I know that he's
authorized to do so? You need an
identity layer that, you know, that has
a reputation stack that could be
entirely digital. That could be just an
agent, right? Uh and we're really
excited about that because through that
infrastructure, maybe we can now
establish the framing that we were
hoping for with Web3.
Better sharing of that value. Mhm. Cuz
right now it's not transparent. Right?
Um you know, Google controls essentially
a much of that supply, right? It takes
you with directing advertising, you have
to pay them all the money. Uh what
happens if I now can freeze through a
token economy? Now you have also
third-party people who can actually also
bet into that, so to speak. Say, "Hey,
you You what? I think this website might
be popular with the data they're
creating. I can actually be an investor
in the asset class of that data, right?
Data is actually and has always been a
commodity, but it wasn't possible to do
so until tokenization.
You know, um RWAs is an interesting
comment topic because everyone says a
real world asset is is a real estate, is
a stocks. Yeah, but you know, for our
children, when we tokenize video game
items as NFTs, that was real world to
them.
Right? It's super it's, you know, data
is basically, I would say, an RWA. This
has never been framed in this way
because, you know, you know, when we
talk about sort of intellectual property
rights and taking royalties and turning
that into a tokenized yield product, we
call that an RWA, but what is IP? It's
entirely virtual, right? So, really, I
think RWAs is a fancy way to try to
connect the physical to the digital
world, but to the human mind, it's all
real anyway. I think in one of your
interviews, you talk about in the future
every company will launch their token.
Is that correct?
>> What I said was tokenize or die.
>> [laughter]
>> Right. Right.
>> meant by that was that if you don't have
a token strategy, if you're not
tokenized, you will lose against the
company that is tokenizing, right?
Explain that.
>> Well, so think about the early days of
the internet when we had this thing
called digital literacy. You lost to the
company that went online. If you're a
media company if you're a newspaper and
the your newspaper competitor went
online, you lost to that guy, right? If
you were selling books
and there was an online book seller, you
lost to the guy who was an online book
seller, clearly, right? Um you know,
predecessor here, right? So, yeah. Now,
the the point being that there are all
these technological shifts that happen
that basically you have to be ready for
to address these new markets. If you
were not on on the App Store and your
competitor who was in the App Store, he
would win against you. If you were on
social media and your competitor was
not, you would win against, you know,
it's it's a classic thing. Yeah. So, for
tokenization, it's the same. But for
tokenization, it's not only because
agents can read your asset, that's a big
one, or maybe that's a youth asset class
that people a
It's also
the fact that you have now new financial
instrumentations available to you that
make it possible to to leverage your
assets, right? Which if you can leverage
your assets that you couldn't leverage
before and your competitor can't do
that,
game over for your competitor, right?
So, that's what I mean by tokenize or
die. Now, if you happen to be fortunate
enough to be in an industry where
tokenization doesn't matter because
nobody tokenizes,
it's all same. But, my point is that if
you can figure out the token strategy,
which we think you will be able to, just
like how you'll figure out your internet
strategy back in the day, right? Then,
um you will you will you will win. And
every company has to think about how do
I tokenize? Because if you don't
tokenize, you'll be left out of this
agentic web. If someone is watching this
episode and they really want to start
their own thing, you know, they're very
inspired by what you guys are saying,
what are some really cool ideas, you
know, you can come up with or any
suggestions to whoever that's watching?
It's a great question. Uh I talked to a
lot of founders and
>> [clears throat]
>> you know, if we're talking about Web 3
in general, um we're definitely seeing
it not being limited to uh you know,
crypto or gaming. It's impacting
everything from uh supply chain
management to database analytics through
um you know, zero knowledge proof and
you know, mining data that's not
accessible before. So, really the sky's
the limit. What the advice that I do
give to founders is you know, pick the
problem,
uh pick something that you're passionate
about, make sure that the economics
work, uh and find product market fit,
right? So, you know, I've even failed as
a founder where I I built something
where I thought was incredibly
compelling. It was also innovative. It
worked. Um but it didn't have that
product market fit, right? And the
economics didn't work, mostly. So, you
know, we were able It was one of my
early stage uh
startups where, you know, we were still
able to onboard, you know, hundreds of
thousands of users, uh but the economics
didn't make sense. So, um you know, just
because you can create a product doesn't
mean you should create a product. So, um
you know, I won't I won't uh try to
guide them into a particular segment or
an or an idea Because I think the sky's
the limit with the tools that they have
today with
democratizing access to technology, uh
the agentic workflows that are coming.
Um it's really uh you know, a one-person
show with almost nothing.
You know, you can can build a working
product and find that product market
fit. And um
you know, I myself, like all of the
other passionate builders around the
world, you should be testing multiple
things concurrently. There's no reason
why you can't do that. If you're
leveraging these agentic coding tools
like like Cursor or or Curo or or Cloud
Code, you can have multiple windows open
and running simultaneously, running
different agent workflows, and getting
to a point where you don't even just
have a POC. You actually have a
production-ready uh
uh tool deployed in the cloud, built to
scale for nothing, right? So, you can
get credits through different cloud
providers like AWS Activate. So, there's
no excuse not to be able to go to market
quickly. You guys are giving out
credits, right? Yeah, we are. Yeah. Tell
us tell us about it. Yeah, so uh we have
uh we offer uh out of the box up to uh
up to 100K in credits. There's
exceptions up to 200K and beyond for
GenAI use cases. So, um yeah, you can
find credits for AWS at uh startups.aws.
It's our it's our flagship program for
founders, and it's not just about
credits. Um you know, the credit part's
important because we want to eliminate
barriers to infrastructure. Uh but it's
also providing uh go-to-market support.
Um it's also providing technical
support. So, um
you know, again, uh our our goal is to
provide the tools and provide, you know,
democratization into lift those barriers
on infrastructure so founders can get to
building and scaling.
Yeah, I mean, I think the one thing I
would say to founders, uh I mean,
there's so much, right? Um rather than,
you know, talk about a specific
category, is you just have to be excited
about learning all the latest new
technologies and just get into it. If
you just If you don't have a learning
mind frame, it doesn't matter what it
is, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Um so, you know, I sounds very trope. Uh
you got to be curious and blah blah
blah. But but it is true, right? Because
you know, you might have a great idea
and you know, you want to solve a
problem. But if you lack the curiosity
to go dive deep into the technology,
where by the way, you don't have to be a
technologist to understand it, but you
just have to dive deep into it and kind
of become and there's this thing, the
ability to become an expert in
everything is so much more available
than ever before. Mhm. Right? Um so
>> can also fail fast. And you can fail
fast, exactly. And you can just dive
into this and then when you use the
tools and you're in that ecosystem, then
you go, "Oh, that's possible and this is
possible." And that's the idea, right?
Um you know, I think the problem a lot
of it is I sort of I
I see it's kind of like the the sort of
the international China thing, which is
like, "Oh, China has a billion users."
back in the day, right? And they're
like, "I if I if I if I sell shoes
there, it's going to do really well,
right?" And you just need 10%.
>> Yeah, I just I just need like, "Oh,
yeah, you need 1%. Yeah, my goodness,
there's a billion Chinese. So, let's do
that. Let's just roll it out. I just go
and do it." And then it turns out it's
much harder because guess what? They
have to go to China, maybe have to speak
the language, maybe have to learn stuff.
Mhm.
You know, get a bank account. Yeah, get
a bank account. Yeah, go go go and meet
all the vendors and suddenly, you know,
through that process of that whole step
after he's done that for, you know, a
year or two or six months or whatever,
then they become an expert. And then
they identify, "Oh, this is how I do
this and this is how I sort of navigate
this." Now, because of AI and because of
blockchain and web3, you can do this all
in your own bedroom. That's right. You
don't have to travel anywhere. But you
do have to go in. So, you know, um we
meet founders who say they use AI and we
see this in the business plan.
And then it's very easy when you talk to
them about actually how much AI are they
really using, right? Are you using AI to
get ChatGPT to basically write your
business plan or use notebook LM from
Google, which is a fascinating product,
by the way. Or are you actually going
deeper with it? How you optimizing those
workflows?
>> It matters greatly because, you know, um
to me, you know, using ChatGPT is what
everyone else can do. Yeah. It's like
I'm great at Google search. Good for
you. But it's not something that it's
not something that gives you a
particularly particular competitive
advantage.
>> Right. Uh because everyone else can do
that, but how are you optimizing
workflows uh is gives you the insight on
you get it or this is what you're doing.
And it's even away from the jargon. Like
it doesn't matter which LLM you're using
per se, right? It's more about what are
you trying to optimize. The LLM will
come to it when you know what you're
trying to optimize for, right?
>> Mhm. Uh and and that's why, you know,
you got to use some kind of framework,
right? You got to start using AI. Um
because you could be using AI just for a
business solution. Nobody said that you
have to program everything from scratch.
If you know what it could do, Mhm. then
you can imagine it. Then you're going to
the rabbit hole of saying, "How do I
solve that?" right? Um and and again
with Web3 as well. We've had so many I
mean back in the early days so many
companies that said, "Oh, I want to
tokenize. I want to tokenize." Have you
ever bought a token? No.
Mhm. Okay. Do you have a wallet? Uh
yeah, I well, no, right?
>> [laughter]
>> It is impossible
>> I see. to have a real conversation then
because they they um they see the
prospect, but they don't understand it.
So, you have to you have to do the work.
Let's say you are a person that is
really interested in this new AI wave
and they want to build a business around
it, but
you know, the analogy I would use is if
you can't build a phone, maybe you can
build a phone case. You can start a
company that sells phone case. Or if you
can't even do that,
can you open a shop that helps people
put on the protector? Like there are so
many different levels when it comes to
the industry. So, I I know that analogy.
It's a niche, right? So, instead of
creating a a segment, you're creating a
supplier to a particular niche. But um
you know, with with AI, I think it I
mean it really could be anything. I mean
it's kind of a non-answer, but it could
be could be database and analytics. It
could be uh scalability. It could be
helping identify um you know, customer
segments. It could scale I mean really
the the sky's the limit. I don't think
there's one single answer. I mean maybe
yeah, you have a different idea. I mean
I I think you're going to
lean on tokenization obviously,
>> No, no, no.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh Yeah, so I don't think there's I mean
in in um you know, the the movement that
we're seeing in the AI impact, I don't
think there's there's a single industry
that outshines the others that can be
impacted or or or or um
capitalized on. So, on the token
infrastructure, the the way we think
about token infrastructure, it lays the
foundation for agentic AIs. Right.
>> Right. So, so take that aside, there's a
there's a model around that. I think
most people are going to be approaching
it from the agent or AI side where the
token just becomes infrastructure to
support them on the transaction on the
system and whatever, you know, to make
it optimized in in that manner, right?
Um but on the AI side, let's say you're
not technical at all. You know, you can
basically just start using one of those
agent frameworks, right? And they're
getting so much easier. So, you know, we
built one called Animal Combinations.
And again, you don't have to use ours,
but this one activates over email.
And we decided to do it over email
because it was an interface that was
easier for you to understand for most
people cuz they're still using email in
their work. And by activating it over
email, I don't go to a website. Uh we
wanted to take them away from the
ChatGPT search experience because that
experience itself limits you, right?
When you So, so if you go into a website
and you're experiencing like search, you
immediately start thinking, what should
I ask it? And that's not the way that
you're supposed to frame it, right? Um
and then maybe there's prompts and so on
and over time, they start reacting to it
and then you start to imagine, oh, you
can do this. I didn't know this, right?
And so many people are surprised, oh, it
can actually respond in this manner um
and and do that. And then when you begin
from that level, the imagination opens
up. It's not about
do I choose Cursor uh or do I want an
abstraction of that like lovable or like
whatever, like these toolings, right? I
mean, there's great amazing you know, 11
Labs with voice, right? Or you know,
you know, with Gemini, the amazing thing
that they're doing on like all sorts of
things you can do as from a tooling
standpoint. Um those are tools
>> Here's a good one, too. Yeah, here's
here's here's great, yeah. Um yes,
exactly. [laughter] Of course,
But what I'm saying is is that that
requires a certain level of knowledge
already, right? So it's like it's like
if you know what kind of car you want to
build because you've basically studied
different cars and you've gone into the
rabbit hole, then you'll find the parts.
Do I need Plexiglas? Do I need this? You
know, which engine do I want to use? You
know, like those those things come when
you know what you want, but you got to
start somewhere. Like you know, I don't
know any car builder that doesn't drive.
Yeah. I mean what
and you have to have that passion around
it. The nice thing about AI is so
ubiquitous.
You know,
was it maybe 5 years ago or 6 years ago
that you know, if you asked your
children what's the top job you wanted,
it was like YouTuber or something or you
know, some social media influencer.
Right? Yeah, yes, of course. Right? Why
was that? Right? Because it was
something that they engaged in, they
were passionate, they could see it. And
similarly,
you know, there's no rulebook
you know, about it, right? But then you
start saying, "Okay, so which platform,
what are they doing?" You dive deeper
into this area and then suddenly you
find your areas of expertise that you
can emerge from that and sort of
optimize. Right? It's the same thing,
right?
>> Yeah, it's making a a great point about
about diving in deep. And and I mean
there's no greater time to do it than
now, obviously. Um but you I mean as you
dive deep, you learn the the limits of
these tools. And you learn you
eventually learn how to use these tools.
But also you learn how not to use these
tools. Right? And so you know,
regardless of the tool that you use, you
know, I truly am tool agnostic as long
as you are using a tool, right? And so
you know, I'm building all the time. I'm
failing all the time.
And and I'm learning how to use them,
how not to use them. I'm deploying
you know, products that are over
engineered, right? That are not cost
optimized. And then what I'll do is I'll
create another project. I'll reference
that product and I'll say, "Okay,
iterate on that. These are the lessons
that are in that." And so, that's that's
not something that was taught. That was
something that I learned as I dove in
deep. All right? And so, the more that
you And you know, the difference between
somebody that succeeds as a founder or a
group of founders or somebody that
doesn't are the ones that are committed
to that learning experience and and
diving in deep, learning, and iterating
potentially on multiple tools
simultaneously. And then once you dive
in deep and you understand, you know,
how to use these tools, how not to use
these tools, what their limits are, what
these limits aren't, at the same time,
concurrently, these tools are getting
better and better. And then that's when
you start to figure out, this is the
path. That's when you also start to
figure out, how does this um
how does this align with what my what
I'm passionate about? How does this also
align with what my resources are, what
my networks is like? And then that's
when sort of, you know, hopefully, if
you follow that process, that's when the
the light bulb moment happens, um and
then you're off to the races. The light
bulb moment comes when you're solving a
problem. Mhm. Yeah. Right? For even when
you talk about I'm hitting the limits of
this. Mhm.
>> Well, how do I work around it? That's
problem solving. Yeah. Right? Is it
another tool? Is it a barrier? Is there
a work around? How do I do it? And this
is also an element of grit. I might not
know how to do this now, but I'll figure
out how to overcome this particular
mountain so that I I get there, right?
And frankly, you know, if you want to go
slightly philosophical,
that's how we will have an edge over AI.
Oh, I like that.
>> Yeah, because, you know, this learning
mindset and this ability to problem
solve on the fly and being able to sort
of deal with uncertainty is not
something that an AI can do because it's
not trained for that. It's trained on
existing models. And it will give you
good choices, but the ultimate decision
framing is yours.
And and if you don't if you delegate
everything to AI, you know, there was
this MIT study that said people use
ChatGPT to get dumber, right? Mhm. Um I
mean, you know,
>> Really? typical headline.
>> Uh-oh. You know, it was a certain number
of people, not all of them, right? I
guess they they they they just looked at
And I I can But I can see how that
happens. You know, if you're basically
just given the essay, if you don't know
how to sort of write,
>> Yeah. and you You the essay to ChatGPT
to write an essay for you.
You You don't know how to write.
>> Yeah. Right? You just You don't know the
principles of it. It just wrote it for
you.
Uh and it may be good or may be bad. Uh
but the point is is that you've gained
nothing from it. Right? You've not
iterated yourself, right? And so the
ability for you to then navigate that
and know how to make it better goes
away. So this idea of schooling through
the hard work, whether it's math or all
or even sort of, you know, the
scientific approach, these are just
methods for you to basically iterate
yourself to get to a decision framing
around the where you can solve these
problems.
And humans are irrational to a machine.
We
make decisions that are completely
irrational. Every major startup that's
built or small startup is an irrational
decision.
Right? I mean, you're not building
something that is certain. You're
building something that's highly
uncertain. You're putting money on the
line. You're wasting your time
potentially, right?
>> being logical, you would have never done
it.
>> Yes. If you were If you're a machine,
don't do it, right? Um because the
probability of failure is incredibly
high. And yet we do that because we're
risk engines. Mhm. Uh you know, I mean,
even, you know, I would argue every
attempt at a relationship, we're taking
a risk even though internally we're able
to calculate that. A machine would
probabilistically say, "No, don't do
that, right?"
>> Yeah. That's where That's where
reasoning and critical thinking come in,
right? And so you need to realize when
to use it and when not to use it. And it
does It does It still is based on, at
least today, um you know, prompt and
output. There isn't uh an evaluation and
a learning feedback loop yet. I mean,
yeah. And that's the differentiation I
think from where we're at today versus
the I mean, I think we both lived in a
time when the calculator was not allowed
in the classroom, right?
>> And the criticism was it will make you
dumb. Yeah. You will not know how to do
math. That's right. The calculator has
made math not just more abundant,
>> Exactly. but the
you know, faster, bigger, faster
breakthroughs in math. Yeah. Because now
more people can do math because of the
calculator and then the computer. Right?
I think AI will do the same.
I 100% agree. Yeah, I mean, it's like
transportation. I mean, you know, did it
But could you should you still keep
walking around or or take a train, you
know, like yeah, I mean You could use a
horse. You could use a horse, yeah,
exactly. The last question before we
wrap up is if I want to build something
do I increase my chance to be backed by
Animoca if I use AWS?
>> [laughter]
>> What a set of question.
Um
well, okay, so first of all um I'm
afraid to say the answer is no. Yeah,
yeah, I know the answer to that, all
right.
>> course. It was we we wouldn't we
wouldn't want to know whether you're
using AWS. We would want to know how
you're using AWS, right? So if you come
to us and say I'm using AWS with this
with this this optimized whatever. I
know the price structure. I can optimize
it and blah blah blah.
That says something about you. Okay.
>> Right? That that's more important than
the particular tool you're using.
>> of course, of course.
>> Yeah, and I I would just add to that um
you know
from a different lens uh to Yeah, that's
the exact point. Yeah, we see a lot of
founders regardless of cloud provider um
you know, making poor scaling decisions,
right? And so the the last thing
regardless of the cloud provider that
you choose as a founder you to be going
through when you're scaling is a
migration. Mhm. And so we spend a lot of
time um you know, leveraging and working
with tools that are they're using
off-the-shelf systems um that that work
quite well uh but they lack the
infrastructure to provide scale and
security. So um again, the last thing
you want to be going through is is a
migration when you're when you're
scaling. And so you you need to start
thinking about regardless of the cloud
provider um you know, what what tools
that you're using that are going to
allow you to to scale uh securely and
safely.
Hey, just one quick thing in closing if
we have time. So
AWS and Animoca are are partnering on an
Agentech uh World Cup of Football.
>> Oh, that. Okay.
>> Yeah, so we were last week uh stealth
mode um but basically uh developers um
of all uh,
sizes are going to be able to go
through, uh, a workshop to learn about
how to develop agents.
Um, and then one of the outcomes of that
is, uh, a game interface that Animoca
has designed. So, the agents will be
competing, uh, in a soccer tournament,
uh, in real time. And we're going to be
running that, uh, at scale globally to
correspond with FIFA this year. So, be
on the lookout for that.
>> And some people might do some Polymarket
bets on the side, I think. I'm sure.
>> I would not be surprised. We got to
figure out how to tokenize this thing.
>> Yes, exactly. Exactly. Yeah. See, I love
this conversation cuz I've learned so
much from you guys. It's always great
talking to you, and my god, I've learned
so much from you, Ian. Thank you, guys,
for you know, Thank you for having us.
being on the show, and please come back
soon. I would love to have you back. You
know, there's so much more we can talk
about.